If your vehicle has met with an accident and
you go to the insurance company and
ask for a claim, will the insurance company
give you the claim without the PUC i.e. Pollution Under Control Certificate? The
answer is no because now the PUC
certificate is mandatory for everything. If
you drive a vehicle, you must have a PUC
certificate. Actually, the Pollution
Under Control Certificate
tells about the health of your vehicle, that is, the Pollution Under Control Certificate report checks whether the
surface of your vehicle is pollution-wise
or not
and it is
very important to have this certificate which you will get
from any petrol pump or
PUC centre. But if you
believe that you will get insurance, then no,
because the Supreme Court has
also said this in its findings and in its
order that the PUC
certificate is very mandatory.
Because according to the Motor Vehicles Act 1989, the
Supreme Court said that
you must have this certificate or it is
made for 3 months or 6 months as well,
but it should be in your hand if
you live in Delhi NCR. Then
this  The time of pollution has started and
you should have this certificate which
tells the health of your vehicle, whether
your vehicle is pollution-friendly or
not. Now it comes to the insurance company.
Insurance companies have also been clearly told by IRDA
i.e. Insurance Regulatory
Development Authority
that if any
person now takes insurance for any vehicle, then it must have a
PUC certificate, that is,
if you do
not have a PUC certificate and have all the documents, then
all your documents will become invalid,
you will have to provide the PUC certificate mandatorily.
Even after this,
what are the companies doing now? Insurance companies are
asking you to provide the PUC certificate at the time of taking the insurance, that is,
when you renew your insurance, only then
you will have to update your PUC certificate
and this is very mandatory.
After this, then comes the turn of claim, if your
vehicle has met with a major accident, the
entire vehicle is damaged, then
when the insurance agents will
come to the automobile company to give the claim, if
you have a car of any company, then  When they come, the first thing they will
ask for is the PUC certificate. This is related to the surface of your vehicle
that how much pollution it can bear,
so check your PUC
certificate today itself. First thing, second thing is that if you have to
renew the insurance, then get the PUC
renewed first, that is, get the PUC done first.
Keep this certificate with you mandatorily,
after that get the insurance renewed. So, that is why you have to
drive a vehicle. If you
drive a vehicle and want to drive comfortably, then
you will have to keep the PUC certificate
because without it you will have to pay a heavy fine.
If ever you are
caught by the police inspector that you do
not have the PUC certificate, then you will have to
pay a heavy fine as well. So, separate PUC certificates are made for two wheelers
and separate for four wheelers.
Keep your PUC certificate i.e. Pollution Under Control Certificate with you today itself.